体温降下来了
Fever's gone down.
宝贝
Baby?
卡尔
Carl?
索菲亚呢
Sophia?
她还好吗
Is she okay?
很好
Fine.
- 她没事 - 好好休息
- She's fine. - Rest.
我们就在这儿 好吗
We'll be right here, okay?
好
Okay.
他们到了
They're here.
他怎么样了
How is he?
他能挺过来的
He'll pull through,
多亏赫谢尔和他家人
Thanks to Hershel and his people.
还有肖恩
And Shane.
如果没有他的话 我们就失去卡尔了
We'd have lost carl if not for him.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
我们都很担心
We were so worried.
- 到底发生什么了 - 打猎出了意外
- How'd it happen? - Hunting accident.
就这么回事 只是一场愚蠢的意外
That's all… just a stupid accident.
惟愿上帝保佑
Blessed be god,
父神耶稣
Father of our lord Jesus Christ.
予其赞美
Praise be to him.
赐予我们的兄弟 奥蒂斯
for the gift of our brother Otis,
馈赠其此生之年
for his span of years,
馈赠其高尚品格
for his abundance of character;
奥蒂斯 他为了挽救一个孩子
Otis, who gave his life.
付出自己的生命
to save a child's,
而如今 这是我们最珍贵的财富
Now more than ever, our most precious asset.
我们感谢上帝
We thank you, god,
愿他在您的怀抱里 永享安乐
for the peace he enjoys in your embrace.
他虽死犹生
He died as he lived, in grace.
肖恩 你愿意为奥蒂斯作悼词吗
Shane, will you speak for Otis?
我不太擅长这个
I'm not good at it.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你是最后一个和他在一起的人
You were the last one with him.
你见证了他的最后时刻
You shared his final moments.
求你了
Please.
我需要听这个
I need to hear.
我需要知道 他死得其所
I need to know his death had meaning.
好吧
Okay.
当时我们快要走投无路了
We were about done.
子弹几乎用光
Almost out of ammo.
只剩下手枪可用
We were down to pistols by then.
我腿一瘸一拐 情况很糟
I was limping. It was bad.
脚踝也肿的很高
Ankle all swollen up.
「我们必须得救那个孩子」
"We've got to save the boy."
他是这么说的
See, that's what he said.
他把背包给了我 将我往前一推
He gave me his backpack. He shoved me ahead.
「快走」 他说
"Run, " He said.
他说「我垫后 掩护你」
He said, "I'll take the rear. I'll cover you."
可当我回过头时…
And when I looked back…
如果不是奥蒂斯
If not for Otis,
我不可能还活着
I'd have never made it out alive.
卡尔也一样
And that goes for Carl too.
多亏了奥蒂斯
It was Otis.
他救了我们俩
He saved us both.
如果说谁的死会有意义
If any death ever had meaning,
唯有他死得其所
It was his.
《行尸走肉》
这个小女孩失踪多久了
How long has this girl been lost?
今天是第三天
This'll be day three.
这是郡里的测量地图
County survey map.
上面标有地形和海拔高度
Shows terrain and elevations.
好 我们终于可以计划下这件事了
This is perfect. We can finally get this thing organized.
划分区域
We'll grid the whole area,
分组展开搜寻工作
start searching in teams.
你不行 今天不行
Not you. Not today.
你被抽了一千五百CC的血
You gave three units of blood.
在这种高温下
You wouldn't be hiking.
你步行五分钟就得晕过去
five minutes in this heat before passing out.
还有你的脚踝 你现在使劲的话
And your ankle… push it now,
以后就得在床上躺一个月
you'll be laid up a month,
对谁都毫无益处
no good to anybody.
貌似只剩下我了
Guess it's just me.
我返回到小溪那 从那儿开始找
I'm gonna head back to the creek, work my way from there.
我也能发挥点作用
I can still be useful.
我开车去州际公路
I'll drive up to the interstate,
看看索菲亚是不是又走回来了
see if Sophia wandered back.
好 就明天吧
All right, tomorrow then.
到时我们再好好找
We'll start doing this right.
那么出去的人手里不能就拿把刀
That means we can't have our people out there with just knives.
得训练他们用枪 我们答应过的
They need the gun training we've been promising them.
在我的地盘 你们最好别带枪
I'd prefer you not carrying guns on my property.
我们不用枪
We've managed so far.
也这么过来了
without turning this into an armed camp.
无意冒犯您
All due respect,
但这附近有成群的行尸游荡…
you get a crowd of those things wandering in here…
听着 我们在这里是客
Look, we're guests here.
这是你的地盘
This is your property.
我们会尊重这一点
and we will respect that.
首先要做的是 设营地 找到索菲亚
First things first: Set camp, find Sophia.
我不想多问 但有个问题必须先说好
I hate to be the one to ask, but somebody's got to.
如果找她后发现她被咬了 该怎么办
What happens if we find her and she's bit?
我们都该清楚到时怎么处理
I think we should all be clear on how we handle that.
该怎么做就怎么做
You do what has to be done.
那她妈妈呢 怎么告诉她
And her mother? What do you tell her?
告诉她事实
The truth.
我会收来所有武器 集中保存
I'll gather and secure all the weapons.
在找到靶场练习前
Make sure no one's carrying.
不要让其他人持枪
till we're at a practice range off site.
但我要求有一个人拿着枪巡逻
I do request one rifleman on lookout.
戴尔是个老手
Dale's got experience.
至少留一把枪
Our people would feel safer,
这样我们的人会觉得更安全
less inclined to carry a gun.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你们带来的药品
That stuff you brought,
还有抗生素 绷带之类的剩下吗
got more antibiotics, bandages, anything like that?
就只有你看到的那些
Just what you've seen.
已经快要用光了 我得去城里一趟
We're running short already. I should make a run into town.
是肖恩去过的那地方吗
Not the place Shane went?
不是 几英里外有个药房
No, there's a pharmacy just a mile down the road.
我之前也去过
I've done it before.
看到那个戴着棒球帽的人了吗
See our man there in the baseball cap?
他叫格伦
That's Glenn,
是我们的活地图
Our go-to-town expert.
让他跟你一起去 以防万一
I'd ask him along just to be cautious.
听说他醒了
I hear he woke up.
是的 他时昏时醒 不过总算醒了
Yeah. He's in and out, but yeah.
他会好起来的
He'll be all right.
那就好
That's good.
你是说真心说的吗
Did you mean it?
什么
What?
你说让我留下来
You said stay.
你是真心那么说吗
Did you mean it?
听着 如果你不是随口说说
Look, if you didn't just say so.
现在就告诉我 我要知道
But do it now. I need to know.
我是认真的
I meant it.
那好吧
All right then.
我听说你跑得很快 来去自如
I hear you're fast on your feet and know how to get in and out.
我得去趟药房 一起不
Got a pharmacy run. You in?
小姐 这里怎么取水
Miss, what's the water situation here?
有五口井
Got five wells on our land.
饮用水直接从一号井里取
House draws directly from number one.
二号井就在那边
Number-two well is right over there.
是给牲口喝的 但是一样很干净
We use it for the cattle but it's just as pure.
随便用 房子后面的发电棚里
Take what you need. There's a cart and containers.
有马车和水桶
in the generator shed behind the house.
我帮你给马备鞍
I'll go saddle your horse then.
马
Horse?
把我们的枪交出去吗
Give up our guns?
你听见瑞克的话了 我们是客人
You heard Rick. We're guests here.
这样你都没意见吗
And you're okay with it?
没人征求我的意见 现在把枪放下吧
I don't recall being asked. Now lay down your weapon.
也许你喜欢在地上滚来滚去 但我不喜欢
You may like rolling over, I don't.
我反正是也得换洗衣服
Look, I have to strip and clean them anyway.
你还要不要学
You still want to learn?
赶紧的
Go on.
好吧
All right.
坐下
Sit down.
把子弹卸下来
Unload your weapon.
检查一下弹膛
Check the chamber.
往外拉
Pull it back.
把那个杆推出来
Push that lever out.
然后它就会自动就滑下
It'll slide off.
成功一半了
You're halfway there.
达里尔
Daryl.
你自己行吗
You okay on your own?
我自己更好 天黑前我就回来
I'm better on my own. I'll be back before dark.
我们现在有了落脚点
We got a base.
可以妥善地制定搜索计划
We can get this search properly organized now.
你是要聊天还是谈正经事
You got a point or are we just chatting?
我是不想你有危险
My point is it lets you off the hook.
你不欠我们什么
You don't owe us anything.
我的其他计划反正也都泡汤了
My other plans fell through.
我们可以给你们腾出点地方
We could give you more space.
在谷仓那边搭帐篷
Set up over by the barn.
不 不需要那么做
No, no need for that.
你们离房子近点更好
Better you stay close to the house.
这话不太好说出口 瑞克
I don't say this easily, Rick.
我们一般都不接纳陌生人
We don't normally take in strangers.
我不想你们以为这是久留之地
I can't have your people thinking this is permanent.
一旦你们找到那个女孩 你儿子身体恢复
Once you find this girl and your boy's fit for travel,
我希望你们可以离开这
I expect you'll move on.
这点我们要说清楚
We need to be clear on that.
你好呀 农场主女儿
Hello, farmer's daughter.
这是药品清单
Hi. Here's your list.
还有
And, um,
还有另外一种东西 我分开写了
there's one other item. I wrote it down separately.
是个人需要 小心别说出去 好吗
It's personal. If we could be real discreet about that, okay?
好的
Sure.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是什么
Uh, what is it?
忘了要说话小心吗 格伦
Kind of missing the point of the whole discreet thing, Glenn.
好吧
Oh, right. Um…
只是我得知道在哪找得到
I just need to know where to find it.
看看女性卫生用品区有没有
Try the feminine hygiene section.
哦 不用多说了
Oh. Enough said.
没问题
Consider it done.
我不弱 也不是懦夫
I'm not weak and I'm not a coward.
我从没说过你是
I never said you were.
不 我在高速上说的话
No, what I said on the highway…
我不知道说的话什么意思
I don't know what that was,
或者为什么要那么说
where it came from.
那不是真实的我
That wasn't me.
如果可以的话
If it's okay, I'd rather you.
你能不能别把我的话告诉其他人
never told anybody about that stuff I said.
什么话
What stuff?
我一整天都没听到你说一个字
I couldn't get a word out of you all day.
老兄 你说我们会有可能
Say, man, you think there's a snowball's chance.
真的找到那个小女孩吗
we'll actually find that little girl?
人生中第一次 我赌有可能
For the first time in my life I'm betting on the snowball.
对
Yeah.
我也是
Me too.
要我们做什么都行
Do whatever we have to.
我不在乎是否要像蓝博（《第一滴血》主角）那样搜寻树林
I don't care if I have to comb the woods like Rambo.
还是过来取水
or fetch a pail of water.
大家都各司其职 各行其事
Everyone kicks in, does their part.
我说的对吗
Am I right?
做好自己那部分 不怨天尤人
Do your part, don't complain.
这就是我经常
That's what I always…
我要是你就不会喝这水
I wouldn't drink that if I were you.
看来我们遇到了位游泳健将
Looks like we've got us a swimmer.
你觉得它在下面待多久了
How long you think it's been there?
久到估计都能长出腮来了
Long enough to grow gills.
我们不能让它呆在里面
We can't leave it in there.
天知道它有没有污染井水
God knows what it's doing to the water.
我们得把它弄出来
We got to get it out.
简单 给他脑袋来一枪
Easy. Put a bullet in its head.
我去拿绳子
I'll get a rope.
伙计们 不行
Whoa whoa, guys. No.
为什么不行 这是个好计划
Why not? It's a good plan.
这是个愚蠢的计划
It's a stupid plan.
如果这个行尸还没有污染井水
If that thing hasn't contaminated the water yet,
把它脑浆打出来正好帮了倒忙
blowing its brains out will finish the job.
她说得对 我们不能冒这个险
She's right. Can't risk it.
那它必须活着出来了
So it has to come out alive?
可以这么说
So to speak.
我们该怎么做
How do we do that?
你们抛锚时所在的公路在这
The interstate where you broke down is here.
这是那条小溪
There's your creek.
我的农场在这
My farm is here.
我们现在面向这边
We're looking out that way,
东南偏南方向
south-southeast.
小溪的这个支流一带我们完全没去找过
We missed this branch of the creek entirely.
如果她往那个方向跑了
If she went that direction,
那就和我们搜寻的地方差出好几里地
she'd be miles from where we looked.
瑞克 休息一下
Rick, take a moment.
过来看看
Come look.
很美 对吧
That's something, isn't it?
偶尔停下来想一想很不错
It's good to pause for an occasional reminder.
想什么
Of what?
随便想点什么
Whatever comes to mind.
我一般都在想上帝
For me it's often god.
你不信奉上帝吗
No thoughts on that.
上次我向上帝祈求帮助
Last time I asked god for a favor.
然后停下来欣赏风景的时候
and stopped to admire a view.
我儿子中了枪
My son got shot.
我不想再和那位万能上帝有任何关系了
I try not to mix it up with the Almighty anymore.
最好互相不打扰
Best we stay out of each other's way.
洛莉给我讲了你的事情
Lori told me your story…
你是怎么中了枪 在医院昏迷
How you were shot, the coma.
但不管怎样你逃了出来
Yet you came out of it somehow.
你没有感觉是上帝在帮你吗
You did not feel god's hand in yours?
在那一刻吗
At that moment?
不 我没有
No, I did not.
一片混乱中你找到了妻儿
In all the chaos you found your wife and boy.
后来你儿子中枪也活了下来
Then he was shot and he survived.
这也没说明什么吗
That tells you nothing?
这说明上帝的幽默感很奇怪
It tells me god's got a strange sense of humor.
它好像没兴趣
He's not going for it.
大概因为罐头肉在被吃的时候
Maybe 'cause a canned ham don't kick and scream.
不会又踢又叫
When you try to eat it.
他说得对 所以行尸不会
He's right. There's a reason the dead didn't come back to life.
袭击我们的食橱
and start raiding our cupboards.
我们需要活人做诱饵
We need live bait.
我说过我喜欢你的新发型吗
Have I mentioned that I really like your new haircut?
你头真有型
You have a nice shaped head.
别担心 老弟
Don't worry about it, bud.
我们会把你整个拉出来
We're gonna get you out of here in one piece.
得是活着的一整个 重点是「活着」
Living piece. That living part is important.
- 拜托你们慢点放 - 没事啦
- Nice and slow, please. - We got you.
你们这群人疯了
Oh, you people are crazy.
你到底想不想把它从你的井里弄出来
You want to get it out of your well or not?
帮我们在这儿看着 玛姬
Give us an eye there, Maggie.
感觉如何
Doing okay?
感觉好极了
Yup, doing great.
像在做梦一样
Living the dream.
再放低点 再低点
Little lower. Little more.
- 抓住 抓住 - 快抓住
- Get it! Get it! - Grab it!
抓住啊
Grab it!
拉我出去
Get me out of here!
别碰我 别碰我
Get it off. Get off.
别碰我 拉我出去
Get off! Get me out!
天啊 天啊
Oh my god. Oh my god.
伙计们 拉我出去
Guys, get me out!
- 加油 伙计们 - 拉我出去
- Come on, you guys. - Get me out!
天啊 天啊 天啊
Oh god. Oh god. Oh my god!
把我从这拉出去
Get me out of here!
- 拉啊 - 快拉
- Pull! - Pull! Pull!
- 拉啊 拉啊 - 加油 用力拉
- Pull! Pull! - Let's go, pull.
把我拉出去 把我拉出去
Get me out. Get me out.
快点
Come on, guys.
- 格伦 - 拉他上来
- Glenn! - Pull him up!
拉他上来 拉他上来
Pull him up! Pull him up!
我把拉出去
Get me out of here!
拉他上来 拉他上来
Pull him up. Pull him up.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
得重新来过了
Back to the drawing board.
说得轻巧
Says you.
索菲亚
Sophia!
- 加油伙计们 拉啊 - 加油
- Come on, guys, pull. - Come on, y'all.
快好了 加油拉 伙计们
Almost there. Come on, pull, guys.
- 加油 - 用力啊
- Come on. - Pull!
加油 大家一起用力
Come on, y'all. Together.
快好了 加油 继续
Almost there. Come on, pull. Keep it coming.
加油 小心点 T仔
Come on, pull. Watch out, dawg.
慢点 再来一点
Nice and easy. Just a little more.
加油 快出来了
Come on, almost there.
加油拉啊 兄弟们
You've got to pull it, man.
卡住了 加油
It's stuck! Come on.
加油拉
Come on, pull!
用力
pull!
我们得封了这口井
We should seal off this well.
这是个不错的主意
Yeah, might be a good idea.
那怎么处理…
So what do we do about…
还好我们没犯傻拿枪崩了它
Good thing we didn't do anything stupid like shoot it.
明天我们还会回来
We'll come again tomorrow.
你知道还有机会…
You know there's always the chance…
别 我不需要再听这样的话 安德莉亚
Don't. I really don't need to hear it anymore, Andrea.
别再想也别再祈祷
Save the thoughts and prayers.
世事难料 卡萝尔
You never know, Carol.
我们可以沿着围栏挂把子
We can hang targets along that fence line there.
后面的斜坡 是天然挡弹墙
That rise, it gives a natural backstop.
是个好主意
It's a good idea.
谢谢
Thanks.
我要多久才能正式拿枪
So how long before I can carry?
别高估自己的实力
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
我最近可不那么有耐性 肖恩
I'm not in a very patient frame of mind these days, Shane.
- 你应该注意到了 - 得了
- You might have notice that. - No shit.
我可不担心你会自我了断
Look, I ain't worried about you offing yourself,
虽然最近你把戴尔老头吓得半死
even though you got old Dale pissing his pants lately.
没错 这我也注意到了
Yeah, I noticed that too.
他是会因为我而
He did come within a minute or so of being blown to hell.
过度紧张 是没错
because of me, to be fair.
听着 我看出来你很有拿枪的欲望
Look, I see you have the desire for gun work.
这欲望能让你支撑下去
and desire will take you a long way.
但你也要注意开枪要小心
But something you need to know, so fire this carefully.
- 我听着呢 - 纸靶子是一回事
- I'm listening. - Paper targets is one thing.
射中不会动的物体很容易
Easy to hit what ain't moving.
但是要搞定一个
But taking down an assailant,
要杀你的行尸
one that's trying to kill you,
是另一回事
it's different.
听着 在这种情况下
Cuz I say, that kind of situation,
它们如果动作很慢 就没什么
things slow down. That's crap.
但如果行动迅速 就靠你的肾上腺素了
They speed up. Adrenalin, ha.
如果你反应慢它就会废了你
It'll cripple you if you let it.
你得利用自己的本能反应
You need to use your instinct.
不能给它机会
You got to rule it out.
总得有一个要死
Because somebody is going to die.
得想办法
And you'd better hope.
由你自己来决定谁死谁活
that you're the one who's making that decision.
怎么做 我是说 你是怎么做到的
How? I mean, how do you do that?
关掉开关
Turn off a switch.
这开关
The switch,
让你感到害怕和愤怒
the one that makes you scared or angry,
还有同情心什么的
Sympathetic, whatever.
你不会想 只会做
You don't think. You just… you act.
因为可能有人正指望着你
'Cause odds are somebody else is counting on you.
比如你的搭档
That's your partner.
你的朋友
That's your friend.
杀人一点都不容易
There ain't nothing easy about taking a man's life.
不管该不该死
no matter how little value it may have.
但你做完这一切
But when you get it done,
就必须忘记
you have to forget it.
我想我还没达到能遗忘这一步
I guess I haven't quite got that last part down yet.
你会的
But you're getting there?
但愿如此
I hope so.
这个地方不错
It's a good spot.
就这里吧
It'll do.
知道吗 通常
You know, normally.
是我一个人做这种事
This is the kind of thing I'd do on my own.
独行侠
Solo.
我擅长做的事 明白吗
It's sort of my thing, you know?
我是孤家寡人
I'm a loner.
- 你没事吧 - 没事
- You all right? - I'm fine.
在井边时我看到你的表情了
I saw the look on your face back at the well.
从没如此近距离见过有人被杀吗
Never seen one killed up close before?
吓到了吧
Guess it's kind of a shock.
知道吗 一路上我们看过很多
You know, being out on the road, we've seen a lot.
可能我们已经有点麻木了
Guess we've gotten a little numb to it.
也许是
Whoa. I guess so…
我去看看剩下了哪种抗生素
I'll go see what antibiotics are left.
清单上还有什么
What else is on the list?
那你开始吧
Why don't you get started?
你呢
What about you?
我去看看有什么值得拿的
I'm gonna look around, see what's worth grabbing.
平常用的一些东西
Just some general stuff.
你找到什么了
What do you got?
没什么 正如我说的 平常东西而已
Nothing. Just, like I said, general stuff.
安全套
Condoms?
你还有个我认识的女朋友？
You got a girlfriend I don't know about?
我吗 没 没
Me? No. No.
那你很自信嘛
Then you're a pretty confident guy.
不是的
No.
不不不 我没
No no no. I-I-I wasn't…
- 我绝不会 - 我有什么不好的吗
- I would never… - Something wrong with me?
没
No.
没有 我…
No, I…
我不会和你那啥…
I would never have sex…
我 我凌乱了
Uh, I'm… I'm lost.
我会和你做爱
I'll have sex with you.
真的吗
Really?
为什么
Why?
你是十万个为什么吗
You're asking questions?
好吧 我忍不住想问
Okay, I can't help wondering.
这年头也没什么选择余地了
It's not like our options are vast these days.
而且不是只有你一个人感到孤独
And you're not the only one that's lonely.
你得再考虑下
You need to reconsider.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
赶我们走的事
Asking us to leave.
你得再考虑考虑
You need to reconsider.
如果你见过外面的情况 你就不会赶我们了
If you saw how it is out there you wouldn't ask.
你是个有信仰的人
You're a man of belief.
如果你真有信仰 就相信我的话
If you believe anything, believe that.
你让我很为难
You're putting me on the spot.
我没办法
Well, I mean to.
那些人有事都找我
Those people look to me for answers.
我希望他们不要 可还是如此
I wish they didn't, but they do.
我不是为了他们或自己来求你
But I'm not asking for them or myself.
我是为了我儿子求你
I'm asking for my boy.
你朋友奥蒂斯已经付出了性命
After the price your friend Otis paid,
至少你再想想
the least you can do is give it some thought.
你这人说话真实在
You're a plainspoken man.
我是个当爹的
I'm a father.
我不想辜负我儿子
He's the one thing I don't want to fail.
我觉得自己每天都在辜负他
I feel like I do every day.
今天早上我对他撒了谎
I lied to him this morning.
虽然不是大谎 但已经够糟了
It wasn't a big lie, but it was enough.
我老爸都懒得说谎安慰我
My father didn't bother with comforting lies.
他直接动拳头
He used his fist.
他是个毫无爱心 野蛮暴力的酒鬼
He was a loveless, violent drunk.
对谁都是个祸害
And no good to anybody.
我十五岁时 他把我赶出家门
He drove me from home when I was 15.
我离家多年
Didn't lay eyes on this place again for many years.
瑞克 他死的时候我都不在
I was not at his deathbed, Rick.
我不会让他得逞
I would not grant him that.
至今我也不会后悔
And to this day do not regret it.
有的父亲注定得不到儿子的爱
Some men do not earn the love of their sons.
我看你应该没这烦恼
I don't see you having that problem.
你会考虑我的请求吗
Will you consider my request?
有些事情
There are aspects to this,
我是不能 也不会商量的
things that I can't and won't discuss.
但如果你和你的人按我的规矩来
But if you and your people respect my rules,
我不敢打包票 但我会考虑的
no promises, but I will consider it.
我向你保证
You have my word.
我也保证
You have mine.
嘿
Hey.
我陪他坐会儿
I'll sit with him.
刚刚你不在的时候他醒了
He was awake earlier when you were gone.
他问你去了哪儿
He asked for you.
- 我… - 别煞风景
- I… - Don't spoil it.
这么说 感觉不错嘛
So it was good.
仅此一次
It was a one-time thing.
- 一切都好吗 - 挺好
- Everything go okay? - Fine.
什么事都没有
Nothing happened.
找到了吗
Did you find it?
我清理了一下
I cleaned up.
想给她个好环境
Wanted it to be nice for her.
我还以为走错地方了呢
For a second I thought I was in the wrong place.
花
A flower?
这是彻罗基玫瑰
It's a cherokee rose.
相传当年美国士兵
The story is that when american soldiers.
驱逐印第安人哭着离开他们的家园时
were moving Indians off their land on the trail of tears,
彻罗基族的母亲们以泪洗面
the cherokee mothers were grieving and crying so much.
因为她们在途中失去了自己的孩子
'cause they were losing their little ones along the way.
因为日晒雨淋 疾病肆虐
from exposure and disease,
还有饥饿困乏
and starvation.
许多人失踪了
A lot of them just disappeared.
所以长老们 即所谓「祈祷者」
So the elders, they said a prayer;
祈求神灵鼓舞母亲们的精神
asked for a sign to uplift the mothers' spirits,
给她们力量
give them strength.
还有希望
and hope.
第二天 这玫瑰
The next day this rose.
就在妈妈们留下泪水的地方绽放开来
started to grow right where the mothers' tears fell.
我没傻到
I'm not fool enough.
相信有花会为我哥哥而开
to think there's any flowers blooming for my brother.
但我相信这一朵
But I believe this one.
是为你女儿开放的
bloomed for your little girl.
她一定会很喜欢把花放这
She's gonna really like it in here.
你好 爸爸
Hey, dad.
卡尔
Carl,
之前我跟你说过苏菲亚的事
I told you something earlier today about Sophia…
我知道了 妈妈告诉我了
I know. Mom told me.
我还准备好认错的呢
Here I was getting ready to confess.
我不是故意撒谎 我只是不想你担心
I didn't mean to lie. I just didn't want to worry you.
这借口很傻
It's a stupid excuse.
但我只想到这个
But it's all I got.
没关系
It's okay.
你觉得我们会找到她吗
Do you think we'll find her?
我知道我们会的
I know we will.
其实
Well…
我也不知道
I don't know.
但我真的相信
But I truly believe it.
你看起来很累
You look tired.
我是确实很累
I am tired.
现在我像你了
Hey, I'm like you now.
我俩都挨了子弹
We've both been shot.
这不诡异吗
Isn't that weird?
是啊 我想你妈妈会更想听你说「我俩眼睛很像」
Yeah, I think your mother would rather hear we got the same eyes.
所以就我们俩说说吧
So let's keep that between us.
既然你也加入了挂彩一族
Since you're in the club now,
你得戴上这帽子
You get to wear the hat.
知道不
Didn't you know?
明天我们往帽檐里塞点东西 就能戴稳当了
We'll pad the rim tomorrow so it sits better.
你不会想它吗
Won't you miss it?
也许偶尔你得借我戴会儿
Maybe you'll let me borrow it from time to time.
我们可以共享
We can share it.
好
Okay.
睡吧
Sleep now.
好
Okay.
我爱你 爸爸
I love you, dad.
我爱你
I love you.
你真要把它们丢下吗
Are you putting them away?
你多陪他一会儿吧
Stay with him a while longer.
我会等着你
I'll wait up.